# MATTEO PIOMBO

#### **PROFILE**

Matteo Piombo was born in Rovigo (RO) Italy, in 1971. Resides in Via Bedendo, 12 - 45100 Rovigo (RO) Italy.

He's always learning something. Developed mobile applications for Apple devices ( iPhone , iPad etc. ). Systems administrator in public and private health companies. ICT teacher in various professional courses. Research and development of custom business solutions involving ICT. Licensed to practice as an engineer in Italy.

### **EXPERIENCE**

ENGINEER AT PIXARTPRINTING S.P.A. QUARTO D'LATINO (VE) ITALY 2016 – PRESENT Software developer.

ENGINEER AT GAVIA SYSTEMS S.R.L. ROVIGO ITALY 2003 - 2014

Permanent contract during which he held several roles:

- System Administrator Azienda Sanitaria (Health Unit) 18 Rovigo
- Development of client / server solutions tailored to client companies
- Operation management for installation and maintenance of telecommunication equipment

He resigned voluntarily from office under the terms of notice and without litigation.

PROFESSIONAL TEACHER - 2001 - 2002

Lecturing to various training courses related to:

- E-commerce
- Website development
- Using SQL to interact with relational databases

Customers: Artisan Training Authority ( EFA Padua ) , Ente ACLI Professional Education ( En.AIP Padua )

### **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF PADUA (ITALY)

MASTER'S DEGREE IN ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING - 1999

Title of master's thesis title: "Actors and influencers in E-Commerce. A model for digital products"

## POST GRADUATE COURSES IN MANAGEMENT ENGINEERING

He attended the PhD program in Management Engineering (University of Padua) for a term of about three years. He interrupted the program due to working needs. During this period he studied the possibilities and limitations offered by Agent Based simulation models for organisational strategies development.

In the context of the PhD program he attended the following graduate schools for PhD students:

- "Industrial economy oriented to the New Economy" 5 days, Associazione Italiana Ingegneria Gestionale (AilG)
- "The organisation oriented to the Learning Organisation" 5 days, AilG
- "Strategies and Operation Management in Enterprise Networks" 5 days, AilG
- "Complexity in Social Science. COSI Summer School" 2002 5 days, GRIC-IRIT Toulouse (FR)

### **SKILLS**

### From the most recent:

- Data Analysis:
  - "Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach by University of Washington on Coursera. Certificate earned on November 19, 2015". "Machine Learning by Stanford University on Coursera."
  - "The Data Scientist's Toolbox", "R Programming", "Getting and Cleaning Data", "Exploratory Data Analysis", "Statistical Inference", "Regression Models", "Reproducible Research" by Johns Hopkins University on Coursera. Certificates earned.
- SWIFT programming language for iOS environments, since the first public beta release (2014). Objective-C programming language for iOS since 2011 years as an independent developer.
- Mobile applications development and distribution via Apple App Store. Integration with third party services such as Facebook, Google, Parse.
- Various skills in ICT system administration. At the time he left Gavia Systems, the most recent operating system available to clients were Windows 2008.
- Various skills in developing web based client / server solutions, including PHP, MySQL, Apache, IIS, HTML / CSS, Javascript)

### **OTHER**

Languages:	Italian: Mother tongue English: Professional
Sports:	Running, Swimming, Rugby

### **REFERENCES**

Personal web site: <a href="http://www.fedro.org">http://www.fedro.org</a>

LinkedIn: https://it.linkedin.com/in/matteopiombo

Twitter: @perlfly

GitHub: https://github.com/perlfly

StackOverflow: http://stackoverflow.com/users/4358829/matteo-piombo

Most recent permanent contract: Gavia Systems S.r.l. Sede Legale Via A. De Paoli, 1042 - 45038

Polesella (RO) Italia Tel.: +39 0425 648452